thetrendspotter.net 2019-11-09

# PRIVACY POLICY - The Trend Spotter

Please read this Privacy & Cookie Policy carefully before using or proceeding to access this website. Your use of this website indicates you have read and understood this Privacy & Cookie Policy and indicates your agreement to abide by the terms herein.

 **INFORMATION GATHERED**

The Trend Spotter (“Company” or “we”) collects certain anonymous data regarding the usage of the website. This information does not personally identify users, by itself or in combination with other information, and is gathered to improve the performance of the website. By way of example, we may use services such as Google Analytics and Chartbeat to collect aggregate information on unique visits, pageviews, browsers used, IP addresses, and similar information. In addition, the website uses cookies to store information about visitor preferences, record user-specific information on which pages the user accesses or visits, and customize content based on the visitor’s browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

Additionally, visitors who submit information via our Contact, or who subscribe to our mailing list, will have their email addresses, IP addresses recorded; these are collected so that we may reply to the submitter if they have a question or comment, to reduce spam, and to send the requested emails to the mailing list subscriber. In all such cases you have the option of providing us with personally identifiable information. Users who choose to sign up for a mailing list will receive regular emails and we may, from time to time, track user email usage in a continued effort to improve our services.

Except as described below, we will never sell or otherwise distribute your email address, IP address, or any other identifying information to outside parties unless required by law.

In the event of a sponsored contest, giveaway, or other similar post, we may collect and share additional data with the sponsor. Refer to the terms and conditions on the specific contest entry form for full details.

 **COOKIES**

We use cookies to personalise content and ads, to provide social media features and to analyse our traffic. We also share information about your use of our site with our social media, advertising and analytics partners.

 **OTHER DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION**

We may disclose personally identifiable information in order to respond to a subpoena, court order or other such requests. We may also provide such personally identifiable information in response to a law enforcement agency’s request or as otherwise required by law. Your personally identifiable information may be provided to a party if we file for bankruptcy, or there is a transfer of the assets or ownership of the Company in connection with proposed or consummated corporate reorganizations, such as mergers or acquisitions.

 **ADVERTISING**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](https://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp)

Third party companies that place advertising on our website may collect information about you when you view or click on their advertising through the use of cookies and web beacons or similar technology to collect information in the course of advertising being served on the website. We cannot control this collection of information. You should contact these entities directly if you have any questions about their use of the information that they collect.

Our advertising partners include, but are not limited to:

  * Google/DoubleClick AdExchange
  * Publift
  * 33Across
  * Rewardstyle
  * Shopstyle
  * Amazon
  * Facebook

From time-to-time, we may embed text or image hyperlinks to these advertisers and affiliated partners, and we may be compensated for views, clicks or purchases made via these hyperlinks. These third-party ad servers or ad networks use technology to send the advertisements and links that appear on the website directly to your browser. They automatically receive your IP address when this occurs. Other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript, or web beacons) may also be used by the third-party ad networks to measure the effectiveness of their advertisements or to personalize the advertising content that you see. We have no access to or control over these cookies that are used by third-party advertisers. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party ad servers for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices. This Privacy Policy does not apply to, and we cannot control the activities of, such other advertisers or websites.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites.

 **NOTICE REGARDING ONLINE BEHAVIORAL ADVERTISING**

We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our website. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioural advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit www.networkadvertising.org.

 **DOUBLECLICK DART COOKIE**

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on the website. Google’s use of the DART cookie enables it to serve ads to your users based on their visit to this website and other sites on the Internet. Users may opt out of the use of the DART cookie by visiting the Google ad and content network privacy policy at the following URL: [http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html](https://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html)

 **MOBILE DEVICE ADVERTISING**

Some third-party companies, such as Google, enable remarketing of ads using mobile device identifiers designated for advertising (“advertising-specific device identifier”). We will collect and pass to third parties advertising-specific device identifiers unless you have opted-out of ad tracking for your device. Details on how to opt out of such tracking may be found at your device manufacturer’s website. If you have opted out of ad tracking and wish to reset the identifier to disassociate the device from remarketing data that was collected and passed before the opt-out, please visit your device manufacturer’s website for details on how to do so.

 **SECURITY**

We take appropriate steps to ensure data privacy and security including through various hardware and software methodologies. However, we cannot guarantee the security of any information that is disclosed online.

 **** **OTHER WEBSITES**

Please be aware that the website may contain links to or embedded content from other sites on the Internet that are owned and operated by third parties. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of websites to which we link. If you provide any information to such third parties, different rules regarding the collection and use of your personal information will apply. We strongly suggest you review such third party’s privacy policies before providing any data to them. We are not responsible for the policies or practices of third parties.

 **USE BY CHILDREN**

We do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Children are not permitted to use the Company website or services, and we request that children under the age of 13 not submit any personal information to the website. Since information regarding children under the age of 13 is not collected, we do not knowingly distribute personal information regarding children under the age of 13.

 **MODIFICATIONS OF THE PRIVACY POLICY**

We reserve the right to modify its privacy policy at any time and will notify you by posting an amendment to the privacy policy on the website. Such modifications will become effective on the day they are posted. We encourage you to frequently review the privacy policy for any modifications.

 **CORRECTIONS AND UPDATES**

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our Privacy Policy, please use our [contact form](https://www.thetrendspotter.net/contact-us/).
